





Summary

Jump to Section

Around 9 years of experience in software industry in the areas of analysis, design and development of Web and Windows applications.

Solid work experience in design, development and maintenance of web based applications using ASP.NET, MC, C#,

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

VB.NET, ADO.NET, Web APIs, REST APIs, .NET CORE.

Hands on into UI technologies like React.js.

Good experience in developing multi layered applications and using design patterns in application designing architecture. Experienced in Azure Devops which includes CI/CD pipeline, Azure Boards, Azure Artifacts, Azure Repos. Worked in Agile Development Model using Azure Devops.

Good foundation with a strong knowledge of object oriented programming principles and object oriented design. Self-Motivated with good team attitude, organized and takes keen interest in problem-solving and trouble-shooting challenges.

Excellent communication and interpersonal skills.

Work Experience

Larsen & Toubro Infotech Limited as Project Lead -Dot Net Jul 2018 to Till Date

Client: OTIS Elevators

Location: Larson & Tourbo Infotech Ltd, Pune, India

Role: Project Lead

Description:

This a project called Customer Portal. It has replaced the old system called eservice. The eservice application was used by all OTIS customers to handle their service requests and manage their accounts and preferences. The new Customer Portal application had UI in React JS and there were 2 layers of APIs created. The UI communicates with Front end API that calls the Backend API which then communicates with the Database.

Responsibilities:

Developed Web APIs in .NET core using C#.

Worked on Report generation logic and sending out emails to users on events.

Root cause analysis of the post production issue and provided a fix for it.

Performed automated and UAT, Integration testing.

Worked on Architecture to design Mcroservice Architecture.

Used Azure Devops for multiple things in the Project

Environment: Visual Studio 2019, C#, WEB API, React.Js, Azure Devops, TFS, GIT, SQL Server 2014

Role: Project Lead

Description:

This a project call GSS Integration. It is about replacing the old system with new Mcrosoft Dynamic CRMsystem. The

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld. project involves creating a middle tier in the .Net for communicating with the legacy systems and the new Mcrosoft Dynamic CRMsystem. Project also involves writing the automated test code to ensure complete test coverage. Responsibilities:

Developed interfaced in C# to invoke the SSIS package

Root cause analysis of the post production issue and provided a fix for it.

Performed automated and UAT, Integration testing.

Worked on SSIS packages

Environment: Visual Studio 2015, C#, Windows Services, SSIS, Microsoft Dynamics CRM, TFS

Fiserv India Pvt Ltd as Technical Analyst

May 2016 to Jun 2018

Client: Insurance companies all over the world

Location: Fiserv, Pune, India

Role: Technical Analyst Aug 2017 - Jun 2018

Description:

This a product called Lifesuite which is used by insurance companies for handling all the insurance policy related operations of the customer. When a new customer signs up for a policy, the policy can be entered into the system. The automatic rules are triggered on the policy which will notify the underwriter different operation which needs to be performed on this policy. The system communicated with third parties using XML.

Responsibilities:

- Solved the production issues related to the product.
- * Root cause analysis of the issue and provided a fix for it.
- * Performed unit testing.
- * Developed a utility to ease the development process.
- * Worked on SRS reports to solve the production issues.
- Did Self-learning on Angular 2

Environment: Visual Studio 2015, C#, Windows Services, Flex, Angular 2, Tortoise SVN.

Client: Lending Banks all over the world

Location: Fiserv, Pune, India Role: Technical Analyst

May 2016 - Aug 2017

Description:

This was a product called Velocity. This a lending product which handled all the loan requests of the clients. Project involved migrating all the old clients from 2.0 version to new 3.0 version. In older 2.0 version, they were using XSLT for data processing. We have to convert that logic to XML by creating mapping files using a windows utility.

Responsibilities:

- * Worked on converting XSLT logic to XML using a windows utility.
- * Worked on crystal reports to create reports from older version.
- Solved the production issues.
- Performed Unit, Regression testing.

Environment: Visual Studio 2013, C#, SQL SERVER 2008, Crystal Reports, TFS.

Infosys as Senior Systems Engineer
Ind 2010 to Jul 2012

Jul 2010 to Jul 2012

Client: Scottish and Southern Energy Location: Infosys, Pune, India.

Role: Sr. Systems Engineer July 2010 - July 2012

GIFT System:

Description: The objective of this project was to provide production support and maintenance for a web application in.NET, which is used by the customer care executives to handle daily customer operations and all the transactions in the UK. This was an application with complicated business logic involving Workflows, Web services.

Responsibilities:

- * Developed interface screens using Windows Forms.
- * Supported and maintained a Windows based .NET application for customer care executives.
- * Followed the Incident, Problem, and Change Management procedures to support environment.
- * Maintained application through multiple release cycles including testing, analyzing defects and developing patches.
- * Provided Level 2 Customer Support triage and ticket management for global servers.
- * Maintained and supported Microsoft Team Foundation Server (TFS) for code to be secured in a multi-team environment.
- * Responsible for writing Stored to retrieve the data from the database.
- * Guiding the team members on issue related things.

Environment: Visual Studio 2008, Web Services, Workflows, ADO.NET, C#.NET, SQL SERVER 2008.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from Government college of engineering, aurangabad in 2007

PG: MS/M.Sc(Science) (Computer Science) from Western Illinois University, Macomb, IL, USA in 2015

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Version Last Used Experience

.Net Core			1 Year(s)
Web API			4 Year(s)
REST API			2 Year(s)
C#			9 Year(s)
ASP.Net MVC			6 Year(s)
React.js			1 Year(s)
WEB SERVICES			4 Year(s)
SQL Server	2014	2020	9 Year(s)
TFS, GIT, Tortoise SVN		2020	9 Year(s)
AZURE			2 Year(s)
SQL SERVER 2014			
Oracle 9i/10g, WS-Access, SSIS			
TFS, GIT, Tortoise SVN			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	
Marathi	Expert	✓	✓	✓	
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓	
Hindi	Expert	✓	✓	✓	
Spanish	Beginner	✓	✓	✓	

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

Work Authorization

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No**

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.